Mss.Rec.57 Mss.Rec.57
American Philosophical Society
Isleta Tiwa material
1965
Mss.Rec.57
American Philosophical Society
2.0 Reel(s)
Four folkloric stories and one personal narrative about the consultant's father given in the Isleta dialect of Tiwa, with accompanying English translations as stories are played back to the same consultant, Mrs. Jojola. Also includes grammatical eliciations. Recorded at Isleta Pueblo, New Mexico, in the summer of 1965.
2 sound tape reels (2 hr., 50 min.): analog, 3 3/4 ips, 2 track, mono; 7 in.
Long, Ronald W.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Ronald Long in 1965. This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Isleta dialect; Sound recordings; Tiwa Indians--Folklore; Tiwa language
- Audio recordings
  - Framed Material: He said ___, 1965; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:21:43; Jojola, Mrs.; Long, Ronald W.
    Scope and Contents note
    In Southern Tiwa, Isleta dialect, only.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Isleta dialect; Isleta Pueblo (N.M.); Tiwa language; Tiwa language--Grammar
  - Framed Material: I see ___, 1965; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; Jojola, Mrs.; Long, Ronald W.
    Isleta dialect; Isleta Pueblo (N.M.); Tiwa Indians--Folklore; Tiwa language
  - Story about Mrs. Jojola's Father, 1965; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:34; Jojola, Mrs.; Long, Ronald W.
    Isleta dialect; Isleta Pueblo (N.M.); Tiwa Indians--History; Tiwa Indians--Social life and customs
  - Story about Mrs. Jojola's Father (Free Translation), 1965; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:04; Jojola, Mrs.; Long, Ronald W.
    Free translation of story told in Southern Tiwa in the prior recording. See Related Recording.
  - The Cottontail and the Turtle, 1965; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:27; Jojola, Mrs.; Long, Ronald W.
    Cottontails--Folklore; Isleta dialect; Isleta Pueblo (N.M.); Tiwa Indians--Folklore; Turtles--Folklore
  - Yellow Corn and Blue Corn, 1965; 02-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:29; Jojola, Mrs.; Long, Ronald W.
    Corn--Folklore; Isleta dialect; Isleta Pueblo (N.M.); Tiwa Indians--Folklore
  - The Fox and the Cottontail, 1965; 02-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:27; Jojola, Mrs.; Long, Ronald W.
    Cottontails--Folklore; Foxes--Folklore; Isleta dialect; Isleta Pueblo (N.M.); Tiwa Indians--Folklore
  - The Wolf and the Deer, 1965; 02-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:38; Jojola, Mrs.; Long, Ronald W.
    Deer--Folklore; Isleta dialect; Isleta Pueblo (N.M.); Tiwa Indians--Folklore; Wolves--Folklore
  - The Boy who raised Tobacco, 1965; 02-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:59; Jojola, Mrs.; Long, Ronald W.
    Isleta dialect; Isleta Pueblo (N.M.); Tiwa Indians--Folklore; Tobacco--Folklore
  - The Cottontail and the Turtle, 1965; 02-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:44; Jojola, Mrs.; Long, Ronald W.
    Interrupted text in Southern Tiwa, Isleta dialect, with English translation.
  - Yellow Corn and Blue Corn, 1965; 02-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:04; Jojola, Mrs.; Long, Ronald W.
  - The Fox and the Cottontail, 1965; 02-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:26:20; Jojola, Mrs.; Long, Ronald W.
  - The Wolf and the Deer [1 of 2], 1965; 02-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:19; Jojola, Mrs.; Long, Ronald W.
  - The Wolf and the Deer [2 of 2], 1965; 02-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:56; Jojola, Mrs.; Long, Ronald W.
  - The Boy who raised Tobacco, 1965; 02-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:12; Jojola, Mrs.; Long, Ronald W.